--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制: 暮雨潇潇 招募Q号: 76846146
传道书云 "欢度青春"
天 那是我想的东西吗？
Oh, man! Is that what I think it is?
好了 新丁 欢迎来到越南 跟我来
All right, cheesedicks. Welcome to the Nam. Follow me.
糟了 有新血
I'll be dipped in shit. New meat!
你们会很喜欢越南的 永远的
You dudes gonna love the Nam. For-fucking-ever.
365天
365 and a wake-up. Oh, lord.
1967年9月B连第25队步兵
在柬埔寨边境附近
下面小心
Watch it below!
莫浩 走快点
Morehouse, drop back to slack.
查理 谁在队尾？
Who's on tail-end Charlie?
总部 这是六队 位置如下…
Eagle, Eagle, Ripper Six, Pos rep follows,'
L、A、W、A、F…
Lemur, Alpha, Whiskey, Alpha, Foxtrot...,
华伦 你去队侧
Warren, you get out on flank.
- 何迈特 - 什么事？
- Hey, Hoffmeister! - Yo?
你有香烟吗？
You got a smoke?
- 没有 - 没关系
- No, man, I don't. - Sin loi, man.
B26 为何延迟了？
Bravo 2-6. What's the delay on point?
又找不到路了吗？
Having compass trouble again?
继续走
Get a move on, boy.
你还在等什么？
Boy, what you waiting for?
他不会咬你
He ain't gonna bite you.
那是越南兵 死了
That's a good gook. Good and dead.
- 新丁 - 新丁
- Cherry. - Yo, cherry!
行动 第六队说我们挡住了他们 完毕
Move it out. Six says we're jamming them up back there. Over.
叫他去见鬼吧
Tell that dipshit to get fucked.
这是第25队 听好 我们很快便出发 完毕
This is 2-5. Be advised. We're moving out shortly. Out.
泰勒 你怎么了？
What's the matter with you, Taylor?
你是个大混蛋
You are one simple son of a bitch.
中士 对不起
I'm sorry, sergeant.
叫另外那个新丁过来 葛拿 还有军医
Get that other cherry up here. Gardner. And the doc.
葛拿 军医 上前来
Gardner, doc, up!
Gardner, doc, to the front!
葛拿 快过来 你他妈的
Gardner, get your ass up the hill, you fat fuck!
大胖子 快点
Hurry up, bubble- butt!
- 你有没有事？ - 蚂蚁
- You all right? - Ants.
我脖子全都是蚂蚁
I got ants all over my neck.
这些是红蚂蚁
You got some red ants.
红蚂蚁是杀手 黑蚂蚁最可怕
Reds are killers. Black ants are the worse.
快点 混球
Hurry up, lard-ass!
我很累
I'm so tired!
只喝一点
Just a little.
不要喝太多 你不要再喝了
Don't drink too much. I don't want you drinking any more.
我不想你抽搐
I don't want you cramping up.
你带着太多东西
You're humping too much stuff.
有一半是不需要的
You don't need half this shit.
我帮你拿
I'll haul it for you.
但请你下次先向我请示
But next time check with me first, all right?
谢谢你 中士
Thanks, sarge.
- 你有没有事？ - 没事
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
这是总部 有直升机接近你们
2-2, this is six, I understand you have a bird inbound at your pos,
总部 请留意
Bravo Six, be advised.
军资直升机正驶来
Resupply helo is inbound at this time, Over,
快点搬军火下来
Go, you people! Get that ammo off now!
这个字不是这样写的
It ain't D-E-R-E. It's D-E-A-R.
而且莎拉也不是那样写的 笨蛋
And Sarah ain't got no two R's, King. Damn, you dumb!
没关系 她会明白我的意思
Don't matter. She know what I mean.
她也不大认识字
She don't read too good nohow.
你看 又是猪肉
Look at this shit! Pork again!
我跟你换你的火鸡 我不能再吃这玩意了
Trade me that turkey loaf for this pork shit, man. I can't eat this shit.
你抽了什么？
What you been smoking?
希望你不用洗衣服 你要运动一下
I hope you don't get that laundry gig. Your ass need to hump, hump.
白小子 你在等什么？
Hey, white boy! What you waiting for?
那个洞不会自己出现的
That hole won't dig itself.
快点掘
Come on. Get your dick skin on that thing!
时间无多 快点掘…
You ain't got all day! Dig, dig!
有人写过 "地狱是不可理喻的"
Somebody once wrote, ''Hell is the impossibility of reason, ''
这个地方就像地狱
That's what this place feels like,' hell,
我只是来了一周 但已经讨厌这里
I hate it already, and it's only been a week,
祖母 这一周很痛苦
Some goddamn week, Grandma,
最辛苦的事就是这星期站岗三次
The hardest thing I've ever done is go on point three times this week,
我不知道我在做什么
I don't know what I'm doing,
我连越共在我面前出现也不知道
A gook could be right in front of me and I wouldn't know it,
我实在很累
I'm so tired,
我们早上五点起床…
We get up at 5,'00 a,m...
整天走动 四五点钟扎营 掘壕沟 进食…
...hump all day, camp around 4 or 5, dig a foxhole, eat...
然后整晚埋伏 或是当哨兵
...then put out an all-night ambush or a listening post,
我是新来的 没有人教我任何事
Nobody tells me how to do anything because I'm new,
没人理会新丁 他们连你的名字也不想知道
Nobody cares about the new guys, They don't want to know your name,
新丁的生命不重要 因为他没有经验
A new guy's life isn't worth much because he hasn't put his time in yet,
若在越南战死 最好在最初几周
If you're gonna get killed in Nam, it's better to get it in the first weeks,
原因是你不会受太多苦
The logic being, you don't suffer that much,
如果幸运 留在外围防线…
If you're lucky, you stay in the perimeter...
守卫时能够睡三至四小时
...then pull a guard shift, so you sleep three or four hours,
但你不能真的入睡
But you don't really sleep,
我认为我撑不到一年
I don't think I can keep this up for a year, Grandma,
我不应该来这里
I've made a big mistake coming here,
我们有很多活动
We got beaucoup movement.
第三部队在15公里外被袭击
3rd Battalion got hit 15 klicks north of here.
越共在树上挂上地雷
Charlie had claymores strung in the trees.
整排军队被炸 真倒霉
Blew a whole fucking platoon to pieces. Bad shit.
两个中尉和一个上尉被炸死
Got two lieutenants and a captain.
我的天
Jesus.
你想谁去埋伏？
All right, who do you want on ambush?
奕礼 你带你的小队出去
Elias, you take your squad out.
华伦 留下 我需要德斯和小尊
Warren, stay in, but I need Tex and Junior from your squad.
知道
Roger that.
调动到20M的位置
Move out in 2-0 mikes.
我以为今晚轮到奥尼尔
I thought it was O'NeilI's turn tonight.
托斯和莫浩经验不足
Tubbs and Morehouse are short.
福生明天放假 还要他们去吗？
Fu Sheng is going on R and R tomorrow. You want to send them out on ambush?
你要带新丁去
You got the fresh meat, buddy.
他们什么都不懂 可能会遇到事情 仔细想想
They don't know shit and we'll probably run into something. Think about it.
太好了 你想我怎样做？
Great. What do you want me to do?
你想我为了一个混蛋要好好睡觉 而让手下被杀吗？
Get one of my guys zapped so a lame ass can get his beauty sleep?
奥尼尔…
Hey, O'Neill...
别再啰嗦
...take a break.
你不用每天都这么讨厌
You needn't be a prick every day.
奕礼 叫手下准备好
Elias, get your men ready.
他来了三年 以为自己是耶稣
Guy's in 3 years, thinks he's Jesus Christ.
奥尼尔 他们留下 但你要去
O'Neill, your short-timers stay in, but you go out.
我需要有经验的老兵
I need veterans out there.
彭斯中士？
Sergeant Barnes?
在他们面前应由我下命令
I think in front of the men, I need to give the orders.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
看来会下雨
Shit, looks like rain.
我们整晚都要在雨中了
It's gonna piss on us all night.
会令你脸烂掉
It'll put a serious case of crotch rot on that ugly face of yours.
你为那个白人而冒险
Goddamn, man. You break your ass for the white man.
这里是没有公义的
No justice around here.
奥尼尔又触怒中尉了？
What's O'Neill got, a nose up the lieutenant's ass already?
为什么总是我们负责埋伏？
Why do we always get fucking ambush?
这是因为他们在玩政治
Because it's politics, man. Politics.
- 我有否给你看过露珍的照片？ - 没有
- Did I show you a picture of Lucy Jean? - No, you didn't.
她会是我的另一半
She's the one for me all right, that Lucy Jean.
她也在等我
She's waiting for me too.
她很漂亮 你很幸福
She's real pretty. You're a lucky guy, Gardner.
你有你女朋友的照片吗？
You got a picture of your girl?
那我们有一个被留在家乡的可怜女孩 不是吗？
That leaves some unlucky girl back home, don't it?
插进去
Tuck this in.
装进去
Shit-can this.
不需要这个 转身
Don't need this. Turn around.
来吧
Come on.
德斯! 跟小尊和泰勒一队
Tex! You got Junior and Taylor here on your position.
奕礼 不要乱来
Elias, don't mess with my pig.
我今晚不是去喝酒 别烦我
I ain't getting greased tonight. Keep this cheesedick off my ass.
你有泰勒
You got Taylor.
葛拿 你和我一组
Gardner, you're with me.
如果你迷路或和队友分开了
ln case anything happens to you, you get lost or separated...
- 千万不要大叫 知道吗？ - 知道
- ...don't yell out, okay? - Okay.
- 不要到处走 我们会来找你 - 好
- Just sit tight and we'll get to you. - All right.
准备出发! 小心谨慎!
Saddle up! Lock and load!
爸妈不想我来这里
Mom and Dad didn't want me to come here,
他们想我以他们为榜样
They want me to be just like them,'
受人尊敬、工作勤劳、拥有家庭
Respectable, hard- working, a little house, a family,
祖母 他们快把我逼疯了 你知道妈妈的
They drove me crazy with their goddamn world, Grandma, You know Mom,
我一向都备受保护…
Having always been sheltered and special...
我想像其他无名氏一样
...I want to be anonymous like everyone else,
为国家效力
Do my share for my country,
就像祖父在一次大战时一样 和爸爸在二次大战时一样
Live up to what Grandpa did in the first war, Dad in the second,
我现在的确是无名氏了
Well, here I am, Anonymous, all right,
和没人在乎的一班人一起
With guys nobody really cares about,
他们来自荒芜的地方
They come from the end of the line,
你从没听过的小镇
Small towns you never heard of,
田纳西波兰斯基 密西西比布兰登
Polaski, Tennessee, Brandon, Mississippi,
犹他州波切本 宾夕凡尼亚的旺普
Pork Bend, Utah, Wampum, Pennsylvania,
只念过两年高中
Two years high schooI's about it,
若他们幸运 会在工厂找到工作
If they're lucky, a job waiting for them in a factory,
他们大部分都一无所有
Most of them got nothing,
他们穷苦而且不受欢迎
They're poor and unwanted...
但他们却为我们的社会和自由而战
...yet they're fighting for our society and freedom,
真奇怪 他们自知是箩底橙
It's weird, They're the bottom of the barrel, and they know it,
所以他们自称平凡人
Maybe that's why they call themselves grunts,
因为平凡人什么都能承受
Because a grunt can take it, can take anything,
他们是我见过最有真本性的人 祖母
They're the best I've ever seen, Grandma, The heart and soul,
泰勒
Hey, Taylor?
新丁 轮到你
Hey, cheesedick, you're up.
- 什么？ - 轮到你
- What? - You're up.
- 你肯定懂得用杀伤地雷吗？ - 我肯定
- Sure you can work the claymores? - I'm sure.
拉下安全栓和撞击三次
Flick the safety off and bang on it three times.
三次 我知道了
Three times. I got it.
不要睡着 否则我不会放过你 知道吗？
Don't catch any Z's on me, or I'll sling your sorry ass! Hear me?
知道
Okay.
或许我终于在泥泞里找到答案
Maybe I finally found it way down here in the mud,
或许我可以从这里重新来过
Maybe from down here I can start up again,
也许我可以骄傲的做个 堂堂正正的虚假人
Be something I can be proud of without faking it, Be a fake human being,
我或许能看见我还没看到的东西 学一些我还没学到的东西
Maybe I can see something I don't yet see, learn something I don't yet know,
我想你 很想你
I miss you, I miss you very much,
告诉妈妈我想念她 柯里斯上
Tell Mom I miss her too, Chris,
小尊
Junior.
- 好了 混蛋 - 轮到你
- All right, motherfucker. - It's your shift, man.
拿去
Here, take this.
引爆地雷
Blow the fucking claymore!
拉下安全栓
Take the safety off! Damn it!
Get the safety off!
救我 小尊 到这里来救我
Feed me, Junior! Get over here and feed me!
- 我的天 - 冷静下来
- Jesus-fucking-Christ! - Easy, boy.
- 军医 葛拿被打中 - 我快过来
- Doc, Gardner's hit! - Right there!
我被击中
Oh, shit. I'm hit!
军医 泰勒被击中
Doc, Taylor's hit! Taylor's hit!
- 糟了 - 军医
- Oh, shit. - Doc, doc!
伤势怎样？
How bad is it?
他没有引爆地雷
He didn't blow his claymore!
放松 只是擦伤 按着
Relax, man. It's a scratch. Hold this on here.
不要骗我 伤势怎样？
Don't lie. How bad is it?
他让他们进入 他当值时睡着
He let them walk right up on us! He was asleep on his shift!
我没有
No, I did not.
海洛老大 留意着他
Big Harold, keep an eye on him.
不要让他休克
Don't let him go into shock.
住口
Shut up!
住口 忍住痛! 忍住痛
Shut up and take the pain. Take the pain!
总部 这是六队 我们被袭击 完毕
Red rag, red rag, bravo six, I have NDPs at this time, Over,
小伙子 你会没事的
Hey, little guy, you're gonna be okay.
不用担心
Don't worry.
你是否知道你会不会死？
Do you know if you're gonna die?
你感到一切都没事吗？
Do you feel it'll all be fine?
胡说 你会离开这里
No morbid bullshit. You're about to get out of here.
他们会给你一日三餐 白床单
They're gonna give you three hot meals a day. White sheets.
漂亮的白人护士拿了你的钱 会给你性服务
Pretty white nurses will give you blow jobs if you pay them.
- 我听说过她 - 不要哄他
- I heard about them white bitches. - Don't baby talk him.
这个混蛋睡着了 他让他们进来
The cocksucker fell asleep. He let them walk right up on us!
小尊 住口
Just shut up, Junior.
放松 好吗？
You relax. Okay, man?
死亡不是…
It's not so bad...
那么糟
...dying.
多久？
How long?
直升机快来了 撑着点 你会支持着的
Bird's on the way. Hang in there. You'll make it.
葛拿 支持着 撑着点 你会没事的
Come on, Gardner, hang in there. You're gonna make it!
别这样 不要放弃
Come on. Don't quit.
别这样 葛拿 不要放弃
Come on, Gardner, help me. Don't give up!
你们好好看看这个狗屎
You all take a good look at this lump of shit.
你们要好好记住这样子
Remember what it looks like.
如果你们行差踏错…
You fuck up in a firefight and I guarantee you a trip out of the bush...
我保证你们不能活着离开
...in a body bag.
混球 在这里要提起精神
Out here, assholes, you keep your shit wired tight at all times.
你也是 猪脑
That goes for you, shit-for-brains.
不能在埋伏时睡着
You don't sleep on no fucking ambush.
下次让我见到有人在埋伏时睡觉
The next son of a bitch I catch copping Z's in the bush...
我一定不会放过他
...I'm personally gonna make him suffer.
我是很认真的
I shit you not.
把他用袋子装好搬走
Tag him and bag him.
我没有睡着
I didn't fall asleep, sergeant.
- 是小尊 - 住口 鸟大便
- It was Junior. - Shut up, chickenshit.
你有麻烦了
You're in big trouble, boy.
借口像是屁眼 每个人都有一个
Excuses are like assholes. Everybody's got one.
别再胡闹
Knock it off!
我们有两个队友需要照料
We got two men need attention here.
收拾好军火和手榴弹
Police up your extra ammo and frags.
不要留任何东西给越南人
Don't leave nothing for the dinks.
背起葛拿
Carry Gardner.
若有多几天去学习 他不会死的
Man would be alive if he had a few more days to learn something.
泰勒
Hey, Taylor.
什么事？
What's in the breeze?
三天轻松任务
Got light duty. Three days' worth.
可惜我们在基地营
No shit. Too bad we're in base camp anyway.
你拿着什么？啤酒？
What you got? Beers?
从长官那里拿的 他偷我们的物资
Stole some from the Top's supply. Shit, he's been stealing it from us.
你回来了？
What are you, back?
看来是了
Yeah, it looks like it.
你从哪里拿到的啤酒？
Where'd you get the beers, boy?
我找到的
I found it.
找到？我会告发你
Found it? You're going on report, son, now.
你们跟我来 有工作给你们
Both of you, come with me. I got a job for you.
混蛋
Motherfucker!
我不适合做这个
I'm too short for this shit, man.
他们总是在玩弄我们
They're always fucking with us.
从没有停止过
No letup.
是政治
Politics, man.
可恶的政治
Fucking politics.
奥尼尔拍长官的马屁 拍的都快成马屁精了
That O'NeilI's got his nose so far up Top's ass, he's gotta be Pinocchio.
39天之后
Thirty- nine and a wake- up.
我就能离开这里
A pause for the cause and I'm a gone motherfucker.
- 回到现实世界 - 很好
- Back to the world. - I hear you.
我过了一百天
I broke a hundred the other day.
还有92天 4月17日
Ninety-two left to go. April 17th.
我便可以回加州了
Home to California.
我会坐在海滩上看美女
I'll be sitting outside checking out the babes on the beach.
冲浪一定会很好玩
The surfing's gonna be good.
三月在田纳西州
March, man, in Tennessee.
可以闻到松树的气味 可以在河边闻到女人的气味
Sniff the pines. Sniff that pussy down by the river.
真棒
Hot damn!
泰勒 你还有多少天？
Hey, Taylor, how long you got left?
- 三百什么？ - 三十二
- Three hundred and what? - Thirty-two.
332天
Three hundred and thirty-two days.
傻小子
Sin loi, my boy.
我不记得那个日子了
I can't even remember when I was 332, man.
你要向前数 好像你已来了40天
You gotta count backwards or something, like you got 40 days in.
想的乐观些
Think positive, dude.
你怎会来这里？你看来受过教育
How in the fuck did you get here anyway? You look educated.
- 我自愿来的 - 什么？
- I volunteered for it. - You did what?
我自愿来的
I volunteered.
我退出大学 想加入越战
I dropped out of college and told them I wanted infantry, combat, Vietnam.
你自愿来的？
You volunteered for this shit, man?
你能相信吗？
Can you believe that?
你放弃念大学实在太疯狂
You is a crazy fucker, giving up college.
我在大学什么都学不到
It didn't make much sense. I wasn't learning anything.
为什么穷人就要去打仗 有钱人就不用？
Why should the poor kids go to war and the rich kids get away with it?
他是个斗士
What we got here is a crusader.
- 看来是了 - 可恶
- Sounds like it. - Shit.
你一定是很富有才会那样想
You gotta be rich in the first place to think like that.
大家都知道…
Everybody knows...
穷人总是被有钱人欺负
...the poor's always fucked over by the rich.
那是不能改变的事实
Always have, always will.
如果你上道 我会介绍一些大头给你认识
If you be cool, I'll introduce you to some of the heads.
什么样的大头？
What are the heads?
晚一点吧
Later, man.
怎么了？
What's up, brother?
大人驾到 发生什么事了？
Your Highness has arrived. What's happening?
我以为你在柬埔寨
I thought you was hanging ten in Cambodia.
你为什么在这里？
Why are you in the underworld?
这个不是泰勒 泰勒中枪了 是柯里斯 他被救活了
This ain't Taylor. Taylor been shot. This is Chris. He been resurrected.
泰勒 你跛了吗？
You lame, Taylor?
你是跛的吗？
Are you lame or something?
继续吧 抽一口吧
Go ahead, old man. Smoke it.
抽一口享受一下吧
Your shit's in the wind, troop.
你好吗？
Hey, man. What's happening?
不是那样叫的
If you do that ''baa,'' you do it right.
你很古怪
You're weird, man.
你是个孩子 我不会在你身上浪费时间
You're a child. I don't waste time on you.
- 第一次吗？ - 是
- First time? - Yeah.
那么你一定会上瘾
Then the worm has definitely turned for you, man.
感觉好吗？
Feel good?
感觉很好 我的脖子不痛了
Yeah, it feels good. I got no pain in my neck now.
感觉很好已足够
Feeling good's good enough.
放入口里
Put your mouth on this.
大家在哪里？
Where the hell is everybody, man?
大家都正在享受 一群毒虫 他们觉得他们很特别
They're getting high. Bunch of hopheads. They think they're special.
你听 很糟的演奏
Listen to that. That's a bad jam.
烦透的噪音 就是那样
Redneck noise, dude. That's all it is.
和你一样那么烦
Make about as much sense as you do.
他们都在埋怨…
All them chucks be rapping about how they losing their ho...
埋怨自己没有钱
...saying how they ain't got no bread for beer.
去他的! 给我黑人音乐 开始吧？
Fuck that honky shit! Gotta get me some Motown jams, dig it?
你干嘛那样说？
What are you talking that shit for?
小尊 你吸食过毒品吗？
Junior, you ever smoke any shit?
对
That's right.
你们想用毒品荼毒黑人
You trying to keep the black man down and string him out on that shit.
但黑人很快就会推翻你们
But the time's coming when the black man will throw that yoke off.
很简单 释放你的心灵就行 你的身体就会跟随
Simple. Free your mind, your ass will follow.
明白 你吸那东西 一切会变得离奇
Yeah, I can dig it, man. You smoke that shit and everything gets weird.
越南人在草丛散布化学毒药
You hear about gooks putting chemicals in the grass...
令我们不再打仗 变成反战者吧
...so we don't fight, so we become pacifists.
不用担心 你怎样都是个杀手
But don't you worry, Bunny, you's a killer anyway.
但我仍然喜欢女人
But I still like a piece of pussy once in a while.
除了赛车 没东西比得上女人
Nothing like a piece of pussy, except maybe the lndy 500.
只有女人死了遗留她的身体给你
Only way you get pussy is if the bitch dies and wills it to you...
你或许才会有
...and then maybe.
宾尼 你好吗？
How's it going, Bunny?
中尉
L.T.
你看
Check it out.
你喜欢吗？
You like that?
很棒
Terrific.
我会寄回家
I'll send it home.
小尊
Hey, Junior.
- 中尉 - 你好
- Lieutenant. - Hello, sir.
罗志杰 你的寺庙很棒
Rodriguez, that's quite a shrine you have.
谢谢
Thank you, sir.
- 你有什么需要吗？ - 没有
- You need anything? - No, sir.
这个人比我大三至四倍
Now, wait. This guy's three or four times my size.
他被奥尼尔勒着
He's in the O'Neill death grip.
他不知道要害怕还是瞎了较好
He doesn't know whether to shit or go blind.
- 中尉 你认为怎样？ - 你好吗 里德？
- What do you say, L.T.? - How you doing, Red?
不好 他拿了所有的好牌
Not good. This cocksucker has every card in the deck.
呼鲁
Full house.
你还不错
You're doing all right.
对 我还没开始作弊呢
Yeah, and I ain't even cheating yet.
- 中尉 要喝酒吗？ - 谢谢
- Lieutenant, some Kentucky windage? - Oh, thanks, Andy.
中尉 你想玩吗？
Play, lieutenant?
不 我不想被你们强奸
No. Wouldn't want to get raped by you guys.
为什么？你留着为了谁？
Why's that, lieutenant? What are you saving up to be?
犹太人？
Jewish?
我要走了
I gotta run.
稍后再见 你们玩得高兴点
I'll catch you men later. Enjoy yourselves tonight.
他真是一个混蛋
That is one sorry-ass motherfucker.
你认为呢？鲍布？ 他能挨过这场仗吗？
What do you say there, Bob? A guy like that make it? Yes or no?
我也是那样想
I have to say that's precisely what I saw.
我只用看一看他就知道了
Sometimes I just look at a guy, and I know he's not going to make it.
他一定不行
Just no fucking way.
1968年 元旦
New Year's Day, 1968,
又是一天 仍然活着
Just another day, Staying alive,
敌军在柬埔寨边境附近越过边界
Lots of movement near the Cambodian border, NVA regiments moving across,
有很多交战和埋伏
A lot of little firefights, ambushes,
我们投下炸弹后 像鬼魅般穿越丛林
We drop bombs, then we walk through the jungle like ghosts in a landscape,
地堡
Bunker.
哪里？
Where?
B2 B25 这里有很多地堡 完毕
Bravo 2, Bravo 2-5, I've got beaucoup bunkers up here, Over,
收到 有地堡 二队在前往途中 完毕
2-5, 2, Roger, Bunkers at point, Two actuals on the way, Over,
B6 B2 前面有地堡阵
Bravo 6, Bravo 2, Be advised there is a bunker complex up front,
我们现在下去
We're on our way down, Over,
下周见
See you next week.
泰勒 去那边五十米以外
Taylor, get your ass up on that flank, about 50 meters.
华盛顿 你去这边
Washington, you cover this side.
- 是 - 海洛 快点
- Yes, sir. - Get off your ass, Harold.
可恶
Shit.
真失望
Bummer!
天啊 看看这个 茶壶仍是烫的 他们刚离开
Christ, look at that. The teapot's still boiling. They were just here!
气氛很可怕 我们离开吧
Man, this is spooky, Sander. Let's get out of here.
小心
Watch it, watch it!
你看我们找到什么
Look what we got, Sal.
有地图
We got maps.
这里有…
We got...
- S2的东西 - 那是越南军的 走吧
- ...S-2 stuff. - That's the gooks' stuff. Let's go!
不 这些东西很重要
No, Sal, this is important. This is important.
我们走吧
Come on. Let's go.
饵雷 伏下
Booby trap! Get down!
军医
Medic!
我的天
Holy gee!
可恶
Goddamn it.
刚才发生爆炸 两个士兵被炸伤
We got two men down, sir. There was an explosion.
我们需要增援
This... We need help, sir. ASAP.
立即离开这里 一轮搏斗你们就完蛋
Move your ass out of here! One round to get you all!
罗德里 乔利亚 快点
Rodriguez, move it! Junior, let's go!
中尉
Lieutenant.
告诉总部我们需要工程师 这里到处是陷阱
Tell 6 we need engineers. This pos is full of traps.
他们快来了
They're coming.
下面的村庄有北越军的踪影
NVA were seen at a village half a klick down the river.
六队说我们要立即赶去
Now, 6 says to get there ASAP.
留下四个手下和军医
Also, leave four of your men here and a medic.
- 好 - 快点
- All right. - Move it out.
召集所有士兵 快点!
Pull the flanks in! Let's move!
曼尼在哪里？
Hey, where's Manny?
曼尼 你在哪里？
Manny, where you at?
我们要在入黑前到达村庄
We had to reach the village before dark,
伊利亚等人继续找寻 和等候工程师
We left Elias and some men to keep looking and to wait for the engineers,
但最后金找到他
But it was King who found him...
他在下游一千码那里
...about 1000 yards downriver, not far from the village,
谜团被解开了
It was the end of the mystery,
混蛋
The motherfuckers.
那个千年村的村民不知道我们会来
The village, which was maybe 1000 years old, didn't know we were coming,
否则他们早就逃走
If they had, they would have run,
巴恩是众矢之的 阿合上尉会经过他
Barnes was at the eye of our rage and through him, our Captain Ahab...
改善事情
...who would set things right again,
那一天我们都很敬爱他
That day, we loved him,
他在那里
There he goes, sarge.
- 把他捡起来 - 好
- Pick him up. - Yeah, you got it, sarge.
快来
Let's go.
不要那样望着我
Get that stupid look off your face!
奥尼尔 清除房子
O'Neill, clear out these hooches.
小猪…
Hey, piggy- piggy. Hey, pig.
宾尼 你要烧掉房子
Bunny, you've got to bring the hooches down.
去右边 小心 出发!
Spread out on the right. Watch your back. Let's go!
这里有什么？
What do you got here, huh?
去那边 快!
Get over there! Move it!
来吧 快点!
Come on, let's go!
乔利亚 集合他们
Let's go, Junior, bring them in.
出来 混球! 行动!
Get out of there, you fuckheads! Move!
来吧
Come on!
- 把他们赶进猪栏去 - 过来
- Put them in the pigpen! - Get over here.
回去! 住口!
Get back! Shut up!
给我手榴弹
Give me your willie pete.
退后
Get back!
准备爆炸
Fire in the hole!
住口
Shut up!
赶他们出来
Get them out of here!
妈的! 这里有一个
Oh, fuck! We got one.
赶他出来
Get the fuck out of the hole!
出来 混蛋
Get out of there. Come on, motherfucker!
冷静下来 他们很害怕
Be cool! Be cool! They're scared, man!
他们害怕？我又怎样？
Oh, they're scared, huh? What about me, man?
我厌倦这样 快出来 混球 快!
I'm sick of this fucking shit! Come on, motherfucker, move!
看看这混球
Watch this fucker!
他们认为我们为谁而战？
Who the fuck do they think we're fighting for?
- 还有一个 - 你…
- You got one more! - Hey, hey!
有什么发现？
Well, what have we here?
我们有一 二 三 四支机关枪 捷克制米克58机关枪
They have one, two, three, four Mag 58 Czechoslovakian machine guns.
他们有二、四…
They got two, four....
他们有足够米粮供应一队军队
Barnes, they got enough rice here to feed a whole fucking regiment.
华伦 带村长来
Sergeant Warren, you bring the honcho over here.
特斯 出来 乔利亚 烧掉房子
Tubbs, get out of there! Junior, burn it!
怎么了？我不会伤害你
What the fuck's the matter? I wasn't gonna hurt you!
我看来想伤害你吗？
Look like I was gonna hurt you?
你为什么不听我说？你他妈的为什么不听我说？
Why didn't you listen to me?! Why didn't you fucking listen to me?!
你这个笨蛋! 你这个王八!
Fucking stupid?! You stupid asshole!
他妈的过来! 到这里! 混球!
Get the fuck up here! Come here, motherfucker!
你在笑什么？ 你为什么不听我说？
What are you smiling at?! Why the fuck didn't you listen to me?!
杀死他们
Do them, man!
你在笑什么？ 想有点可笑的东西？
What are you smiling at?! You want something to smile at, huh?!
- 想有点可笑的东西？ - 对
- You want something to smile at?! - That's right!
- 混蛋 跳舞吧 - 对
- Dance, motherfucker! - Yeah!
跛子 跳舞吧
Dance, one-legger!
跳舞…
Dance! Dance!
跳舞 跛子
Dance! One-legged motherfucker!
来吧
Come on. Come on, let's go, man.
他妈的! 他在嘲笑你
Fucking pussy, man! He's laughing at you!
越南人是那样笑的
That's the way the gook laughs.
当然了
Yeah, sure you are!
你很后悔吧？
You're real sorry, ain't you?
你为曼尼他们的死感到内疚吧？
You're just crying your little hearts out about Sandy and Sal and Manny.
宾尼 算了吧？我们走!
Forget about it, Bunny, huh? Let's go.
你说呢？
What do you say?
妈的! 你看到他的头颅是怎样爆开的吗？
Holy shit! You see that fucking head come apart, man?
我从来没见过那样的脑袋
I never seen brains like that before, man.
我打赌一定是她指挥一切的
I bet you the old bitch runs the whole fucking show.
大概是她割开曼尼的喉咙 她一定也想把我的睾丸割掉
She probably cut Manny's throat. Probably cut my balls off if she could.
宾尼 离开吧 没有人看到什么
Bunny, we leave now, nobody saw a thing!
泰勒 你明白吗？
You understand, Taylor?
杀死她吧 杀死整条村的人
Come on, let's fucking do her! Let's do the whole fucking village!
这个越南人头目脸上有些疤痕
There's scars on this gook honcho, sarge.
特斯 出来
Get out of here, Tubbs.
他从哪里弄到伤痕？
Where did he get these wounds?
- 他说他在轰炸中受伤 - 他一定是北越的人
- Says he was hit in a bombing raid. - He's a dink for sure.
问他这里为什么会有武器
Ask him why these weapons are here.
他们没有选择 北越杀了抗命的老头目
They had no choice. The NVA killed the old honcho when he said no.
- 他说那些米是属于他们 - 莱纳 胡说
- He says all the rice is theirs. - Oh, bullshit, Lerner.
我们在河边杀死的越军是谁？
Who the hell was the gook we nailed on the riverbank?
他不知道 北越军几个月没来过
He doesn't know. The NVA ain't been here in a couple of months.
- 或许他是哨兵 - 当然了
- Maybe he was a scout. - Yeah, sure. A scout.
那些米和武器是给谁的？
What about the rice and the weapons?! Who they for?!
北越军
An NVC!
他知道我在说什么吧？
That cocksucker knows what I'm saying. Don't you?
他一定知道
Goddamn right he does.
他在说谎
He's lying!
杀死他 看谁会说真话
Waste the fucker! Then see who talks.
他说他什么都不知道
Look, he says he doesn't know anything.
他讨厌北越 但他们擅自来这里
He hates the NVA, but they come when they want and take over.
她在说什么？
What's the bitch saying?
她问我们为什么要杀死猪
She's going on about why we killed the pigs...
他们是农夫 要养活自己
...they're farmers, they have to make a living....
住口
Shut up!
叫她住口
Shut her the fuck up!
你叫他快点说 否则我会杀死更多人
You tell him to start talking or I'll waste more of them.
莱纳 告诉他
Tell him, Lerner!
让我们大开杀戒
Let us in on this, all right?
我们杀死整条村吧
Let's go for it! Let's do the whole fucking village!
中士 我们还在等什么？
Come on, sarge. What the fuck are we waiting for?
- 杀死他们 - 走开
- Let's do them! - Out of my way!
这是他的女儿吧？
This is his daughter, right? Right?
你说谎! 不 你说谎! 你这个越共!
You lie! No, you lie! You VC!
巴恩
Barnes!
你他妈的在做什么？
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
别管闲事 这和你无关
Stay out of this. It ain't your show.
你不是火枪队 猪哥!
You ain't a firing squad, you piece of shit!
- 打倒他 - 巴恩 加油
- Get him! - Come on, Barnes!
打倒他! … 打烂他的头!
Get him! Get him! Tear his fucking head off!
伊利亚 杀死他
Come on, Elias. Send him to hell!
妈的! 别这样! 停手!
Goddamn it! Come on, break it up!
停手
Break it up!
伊利亚 冷静点
Elias, chill.
伊利亚 你死定了 我发誓 你死定了
You're dead, Elias! I swear to fucking God, you're dead!
你会坐牢的
You! You're gonna do time in LBJ!
这件事不会就此罢休的 混蛋
This shit won't wash, you puke!
停手! …住口!
Break it up! Break it up! Shut up!
停手 留心听着
Break it up! Listen up!
上尉说烧掉这里 听到了吗？
Captain says to torch this place, hear that?
烧掉这里
Torch this place!
烧掉武器
Blow the weapons in place!
集合他们 我们时间不多
Round up suspected VC and shake it up! We ain't got much light left!
中尉 你为什么不作出行动？
Lieutenant, why the fuck didn't you do something?
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
你知道我在说什么
You know what the fuck I'm talking about.
不 我不知道 我不知道你他妈的在说什么
No, I don't. I don't know what the fuck you're talking about, Elias.
快点出发! 快! 听到命令了吧!
Move it out! Let's go! You heard the lieutenant!
泰勒 走了 妈的! 烧掉武器 然后离开
Taylor, let's go, for chrissake! Police up the weapons and let's go!
哈洛 来吧
Come on, Harold.
准备爆炸
Fire in the hole!
来吧
Hey, come on.
妈的! 滚开
You fucker! Get out of here!
滚开! …不要那样做
Get the fuck off! Don't do it! Don't do it!
混蛋 这是什么一回事？
You fucker! What is this, huh?!
你是同志吗？
You a homosexual?
你怎么了？她是越南人
What's your problem? She's a fucking dink.
她是人类! 去你的!
She's a fucking human being, man! Fuck you!
泰勒 你这个可恶的新兵
Total fucking cherry, Taylor!
妈的禽兽! 你们全部都是禽兽!
Fucking animal! All of you! You're fucking animals!
混蛋
Fucking lame fuck!
你不属于越南 这里不适合你
You don't belong in the Nam. This ain't your place.
你们一点都不明白吧？
You don't fucking get it, do you?
你们不明白
You just don't fucking get it.
没事的
It's okay.
离开吧
Get out of there!
出发吧
Police up your dicks and let's go.
- 我什么都看不见 - 我看到
- I didn't see anything, sir. - I did.
巴恩中士说那个是北越兵
Sergeant Barnes reported the dink as NVA.
我的报告中 沃夫上尉是目击证人
My report will have Lieutenant Wolfe as being witness to the shooting.
伊利亚 好
All right, Elias.
- 巴恩中士 - 是
- Staff Sergeant Barnes. - Sir!
我们回到总部后 我要详细报告
I want a full report from you when we get back to the CP.
你有日志 我有很多目击证人
You got a diary. I have plenty of eyewitnesses, sir.
不是现在
Not now, goddamn it! Not now!
我们回到总部才调查这件事
We'll get into this at the base camp.
我保证如果发现非法杀戮…
I can promise you, if I find out there was an illegal killing...
一定会有军事法庭
...there will be a court-martial.
现在我要全军作战 你们别再吵
Right now, I need every man in the field, and you two will cease fire.
巴恩和伊利亚中士 听到吗？
Staff Sergeant Barnes. Sergeant Elias. You hear me?
- 是 - 知道
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
明天你们从东面再去那越共地堡
We're going back into that NVA bunker tomorrow, this time from the east.
你们休息一下 晚上七点钟回来开会
You people get some rest, and be back here at the CP at 19:00 for a briefing.
- 是 - 是
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
你认为他们会在乎我们吗？
Come on, man! You think these chucks give a fuck about you and me?
哈洛 也许会是你阻碍了巴恩
It could have been you, Harold, you got in Barnes' way.
那个宾尼呢？
And that Bunny?
他是疯的
That motherfucker's crazy.
他令我不寒而栗
I mean, he scares me.
他很可怕
He just scares me.
你已经受牵连
You bloods are getting too hung up on this shit.
这些越南人比你想像中聪明
These gooks are a lot smarter than you think.
巴恩知道他在做什么
You know, Barnes knows his shit, man.
他们是北越兵
They was NVA, every last of them.
他带领我们走到这里了 他会带领我们走完这场战争
He got us this far. He'll get us the rest of the way.
我不知道
I don't know, Holmes.
基督教徒不会到处杀人
A Christian don't go around a village, cutting off heads and shit.
情况失去控制了 完全失控了
This shit is really getting out of hand, blowing out of control.
看来你不知道怎样分别…
Seems to me that you don't seem to know the difference...
事情的轻重
...the way you always shoot up that shit.
我不知道…
I don't know, brothers...
但我内心大受伤害
...but I'm hurting real bad inside.
别担心 伊利亚不能证明什么
Don't worry, sarge. Elias won't be able to prove a thing.
他是个麻烦制造者
He's a troublemaker.
伊利亚像华盛顿的政客…
Elias is a water walker. Like them politicians in Washington...
想独力打这场仗
...trying to fight this war with one hand tied around their balls.
这里没有时间进行审讯
Ain't no need or time for a courtroom out here.
- 中士 - 谢谢你
- Sarge. - Thanks, Bun.
情况怎样？
How did it go there, Bob?
那个可恶的伊利亚
Yeah, thataway, sarge! Fucking Elias, man.
他是个卑鄙小人
He's a fucking rat, that's what he is.
他会连累这个连的所有人
He'll get everybody in this platoon in deep shit.
有人要教训他
Somebody ought to frag his ass.
你认为呢？ 会有调查吗？
So, what do you think? Gonna be an investigation or what?
鲍布？
Bob?
你太担心了 中士会解决他
O'Neill, you worry too much. Sarge will take care of him.
今晚天色很美
It's a beautiful night.
我喜欢这里的夜晚
Yeah, I love this place at night.
繁星…
The stars....
它们没有对与错 它们就是在那里
There's no right or wrong in them. They're just there.
你的比喻很好
That's a nice way of putting it.
巴恩憎恨你吧？
Barnes has it in for you, huh?
巴恩相信他所做的一切
Barnes believes in what he's doing.
你呢？你相信吗？
And you? Do you believe?
1965年时吗？我会相信
ln '65? Yeah.
现在呢？
Now?
不相信
No.
今天所发生的事只是开始
What happened today is just the beginning.
我们会输掉这场仗
We're gonna lose this war.
不会吧
Come on.
你真的认为我们会输？
You really think so? Us?
我们欺负别人太久了
We've been kicking other people's asses for so long...
现在轮到我们被打击
...I figure it's time we got ours kicked.
我每天都在挣扎
Day by day, I struggle to maintain...
我努力维持体力和意志
...not only my strength, but my sanity,
一切都很模糊
It's all a blur,
我没有气力写信
I have no energy to write,
我不能分辨对与错
I don't know what's right or wrong anymore,
我们的士气低落 出现内讧
The morale of the men is low, A civil war in the platoon,
一半支持伊利亚 一半支持巴恩
Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes,
有很多猜忌和憎恨
There's a lot of suspicion and hate,
我们竟然在自伤残杀
I can't believe we're fighting each other instead of them,
数着日子和留意着周遭 没别的
Counting days and the six inches in front of my face, Not much else,
祖母 希望你一切安好
Hope things are well, Grandma,
告诉妈妈和爸爸…
Tell Mom and Dad I...
你知道告诉他们什么的 柯里斯上
Well, just tell them, Chris,
我知道你以为会被派去洗衣服
Hey, big boy. I know you thought you had that laundry gig all laid out.
我要把自己涂白 才能得到那些工作
Hell, I gotta paint myself white just to get one of those jobs.
我递了申请去割包皮 我要离开
Got my request in for a circumcision. I'm getting my big ass out of here.
你会成为犹太教教士吗？
What are you gonna do, become a rabbi?
水蛭
Leech.
继续走
All right! Move it out!
不要喝 你会得痢疾
Don't drink that, asshole. You're gonna get malaria.
我希望会
Yeah, I hope so.
去吧
Let's go.
军医 莱纳被击中
Doc! Up here! Lerner's hit!
中士 华伦被击中
Sergeant, Warren's hit!
- 发生什么事？ - 他们有火箭榴弹
- What's going on? - They got RPGs, man!
他们已在这里埋伏了很久
It's an ambush! They were just waiting for us here!
- 谁负责防守？ - 莱纳和华伦
- Who's on point? - Lerner and Warren.
你去哪里？
Where are you going?!
天啊! 混球! 派火力上前
Goddamn it, you assholes! Get some firepower up there!
对
Right!
小心 火箭炮
Watch out! Rockets!
莱纳在哪里？
Where the fuck is Lerner?
他在木头那边
He's over there! By the log!
开火坐标649602
Fire mission. Grid: 6- 4- 9- 4- 0- 2.
方向610
Direction: 6- 1 - 0...
调整发射 完毕!
Adjust fire. Over.
中尉 他们会步步进逼
Lieutenant, they'll get in tight under the arty!
我看到缺口 让我带人去那边
I saw a cut. Let me take some men and roll up that flank.
叫巴恩去 我们已有四个人受伤 你要我怎么办？
Get Barnes! Elias, we got four down. What do you want me to do?
红连在哪里？叫那些混蛋赶来
Where the fuck is Red Platoon?! Tell those assholes to get up here!
伊利亚 你在这里做什么？
Elias, what are you doing back here?
第三连在这里 我们在这里
There's holes back here, 3rd Platoon's coming up here, we're here!
若越军进入这些洞 我们就要交锋
Dinks get in these holes, we'll be in a crossfire.
- 我们会互相开火 - 听来很不寻常
- We'll shoot each other. - Sounds far- out to me.
我在1966年的战役里见过
I've seen it happen. la Drang in '66.
他们会击溃我们 我需要三个人
They cut us to pieces. I need three men.
好 去吧
You got them! Take off!
继续掩护我们
You keep pouring off that cover fire.
我不想在外面孤军作战
I don't want to be stuck out there with my ass hanging in the breeze.
伊利亚 不要教我怎样打仗
You don't tell me how to run my war, Elias.
你去呼喝你的手下好了
You go crying to fucking brigade on your own time.
在这里你属于我 快行动!
Out here you belong to me! Now, move!
巴恩 你是个混蛋
You're an asshole, Barnes.
叫奥尼尔上前来
Get that asshole O'Neill up here!
可恶
Holy fuck,
伏下
Stay down!
子弹…
Ammo! Ammo!
中士 子弹不够
Sarge! Short round!
混蛋
Fucking idiot!
拿出来
Get it out!
军医
Medic!
有地雷
Satchel charge!
军医
Doc!
- 军医 过来帮我 - 好
- Doc, help me out. - All right, down.
天
Jesus.
- 你没事吧？ - 不要留下我
- You okay? - Don't leave me, man.
- 你会没事的 - 不要留下我
- You all right? - Don't leave me, man.
- Hey, Gator, you'll be okay, man. - Don't leave me, man.
你会没事的
Gator? Gator, you'll be okay.
放开他
Let him go, man.
- 别吵 - 泰勒 你跟我们来
- Drop your rucks. - Taylor, you're coming with us.
求你不要走
Please don't go.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
来吧
Come on.
军医 照顾他
Doc, take care of him, man.
炮手 B2实际射程
Redleg, Redleg. Ripper Bravo 2 actual.
调整方位 B…
Adjustment follows: Bridge....
你这个自大混蛋
You ignorant asshole!
你给他们什么座标？
What the fuck coordinates are you giving?
你的座标已经令很多人受伤
You wasted a lot of people up there with your fucked- up fire mission!
你知道吗？
Do you know that?
你知道吗？妈的!
Do you know that? Ah, shit!
炮手 这是B2
Redleg! Redleg! Ripper Bravo 2.
停火…
Check your fire! Check your fire!
他们来了
They're coming.
坚守这里 枪杀任何走动着的东西
Stagger yourself across this line. Shoot anything that moves.
他们会从那里过来
They'll be coming from over there.
只要被他们攻破 我们便死定了
Any one of them gets through, we are truly fucked.
你去哪里？
Where the hell are you going?
到下游大约一百米处…
Down by the river about 100 meters...
以防他们准备从外围进攻
...in case they try to flank us.
第三连正在后面赶来
3rd Platoon is coming behind us. Watch for them.
我可以和你一起去吗？
Hey. Can I go with you?
不 我单独行事较敏捷
No. I move faster alone.
让炮兵队来处理
Let's let arty do a bit of the work.
叫所有人去教堂…
Tell everyone to pull back to the church...
和第三连会合 知道吗？
...and link up with 3rd Platoon. You got that?
伊利亚怎样？他会孤立无援
What about Elias? If we pull back, he'll be cut off.
中尉 你也快去
You just haul ass too, lieutenant.
我去找他
I'll get him.
去吧
Come on,
- 我击中两个 - 我击中一个
- I got two of them fuckers, man. - I got one.
打倒胡志明
Ho Chi Minh sucks dead dick!
克罗福
Crawford!
糟了
Oh, man. Oh, man.
妈的 我从没想过会被击中的
Kiss my ass. Man, I never thought I'd get hit.
你击中两个混蛋
A lung, babe. You got two of them fuckers.
伊利亚在哪里？一班越兵刚经过
Where's Elias? A bunch of gooks came through here.
- 我们击中三个 - 对
- We got three of them fuckers. - Hey!
炮兵队调动了 我们要撤退
The arty shifted. We're pulling back.
扶伤者去教堂
Get your wounded man and get the fuck back to church.
- 伊利亚在外面 - 我会去找他
- Elias is still out there. - I'll get him.
在我送你去军法审判之前 快扶克罗福进去 快
Get Crawford in now before I Article 1 5 both your asses. Move.
快点
Move it!
快到达了 快
Almost there, brother. Come on.
军医 你在哪里？
Medic, where the fuck are you?
你很快会没事
It's gonna be all right in a minute.
泰勒 你去哪里？
Taylor, where are you going?
伊利亚死了
Elias is dead.
和他们一起撤退
Fall back with the platoon.
快点
Get going.
他死了？
He's dead?
对 他在一百米外
Yeah, he's back there about 100 meters.
你看到他吗？哪里？
You saw him? Where?
他死了 到处都是越军 快走
He's dead! There's gooks all over the goddamn place! Get moving!
来吧
Let's go! Come on, move it!
走吧! 快! 快走!
Let's go! Move it! Okay, let's go!
哈洛 你没事吧？下一个轮到你
You okay, Harold? You're on the next one! You're okay, bud!
糟了
Oh, fuck!
他们抓到伊利亚
They've got Elias!
什么？
What?
退后…
Back down! Back down there!
蛇1- 9队、飞行4 下面仍然有一个士兵
Snake 1- 9, Fly 4, There's still one of the men down there,
停火…
Hold your arms, Guns, hold off,
他杀死他
He killed him.
我知道是他 我看到他的眼神
I know he did. I saw his eyes when he came in.
你怎知不是越兵？你没有证据
How do you know the dinks didn't get him? You got no proof.
证据就在他的眼神 我看得出
Proof's in the eyes. When you know, you know.
你也看见 我知道你在想什么
You saw. I know what you were thinking.
我们今天解决他
I say we frag him tonight.
我赞成 以牙还牙
I go with that. An eye for an eye.
让军事法庭处理吧
I say let military justice do the job on him.
去他的军事法庭! 你在说笑吗？
Come on, fuck the military justice! Are you joking me?
他们会相信谁？奥尼尔？宾尼？ 全是胡说!
Whose story you think they'll believe? O'NeilI's? Bunny's? Bullshit!
巴恩不会放过你的
You try that, Barnes will shove it back up your ass, with a candle on it.
你认为我们应怎做？
What do you suggest we do?
你们小心 巴恩会一个个地解决他们
Watch your own asses. Barnes will be coming down on all of them.
你们忘记和伊利亚的美好日子吗？
You gonna forget about Elias? All the good times we had here?
你想把头砍下来治头痛？
Shit, you trying to cure the headache by cutting off the head.
伊利亚没有叫你为他打仗
Elias didn't ask you to fight his battles for him.
如果真的有天堂 天啊 我希望真的有
And if there's a heaven, and God, I hope there is...
他会在上面喝到大醉
...he's sitting up there drunk as a fucking monkey and smoking shit...
因为他把痛苦留在这里
...because he left his pains down here.
你错了 总之巴恩是杀人凶手
You're wrong! Anyway you cut it, Barnes is a murderer!
- 对 - 泰勒…
- Right on. - Taylor...
你当初入伍时说很欣赏巴恩
...when you first came in here, you told me how you admired the bastard.
- 我错了 - 你做任何事都是错的
- I was wrong. - You've never been right about nothing!
你们这班混蛋 留心听着
Dig this, you assholes, and dig it good.
巴恩中枪七次都没有死去
Barnes been shot seven times, and he ain't dead.
那对你有意思吗？
Does that mean anything to you?
巴恩是不会死的
Barnes ain't meant to die.
唯一能杀死他的是他自己
The only thing that can kill Barnes is Barnes.
你们在谈死亡吗？
Talking about killing?
你们是专家吗？
You all experts?
你们都知道杀戮吗？
You all know about killing?
我想听听 猪头
Well, I'd like to hear about it, potheads.
你们抽这个来逃避现实？
You smoke this shit to escape from reality?
我不需要这个
Me, I don't need this shit.
我就是现实
I am reality.
现实应该是这样 而现实就是这样
There's the way it ought to be, and there's the way it is.
伊利亚满口一派胡言
Elias was full of shit.
伊利亚是个斗士
Elias was a crusader.
我不会跟听从命令的人作对
Now, I got no fight with any man who does what he's told.
但当他不听命时…
But when he don't...
运作便会崩溃
...the machine breaks down.
运作崩溃时 我们就会崩溃
And when the machine breaks down, we break down.
我不会许容那样的事
I ain't going to allow that.
你们任何一个都不能
From any of you.
一个都不可以
Not one.
你们都爱伊利亚
You all love Elias.
你们想为他报仇
You want to kick ass.
我独个儿在这里
Well, here I am. All by my lonesome.
没有人会知道
And ain't nobody gonna know.
你们六个对我一个
Six of you boys against me.
杀我吧
Kill me.
我卑视你们
I shit on all of you.
混蛋
You motherfucker!
打吧
Come on, man.
柯里斯 打他
Get him, Chris.
巴恩 不要下手
Easy, Barnes. Don't do it, man!
你要坐牢的
You'll go dinky dau in LBJ, man.
杀军人要坐十年牢 十年
Ten years for killing an enlisted man. Ten years.
你想想吧
Climb the fucking walls, man.
不要下手
Don't do it.
死亡？
Death?
你们对死亡有什么认识？
What do you all know about death?
我们翌日被派回到山谷里
They sent us baCk into the valley the next day...
进入离柬埔寨约二千米的战区
...about 2000 meters from Cambodia into a battalion perimeter,
我们好像回到案发现场
It felt like we were returning to the sCene of a Crime,
A连在前一天被重击
Alpha Company had been hit hard the day before by a sizable forCe,
C连在那一天被袭击
Charlie Company had been probed that night,
山谷里有其他战事…
There were other battalions in the valley...
但我们是引他们出来的饵
...but we knew we were the bait to lure them out,
141北越军就在下面某处
Somewhere out there was the entire 141st NVA regiment,
他们昨晚想袭击C连
Caught them trying to pull some shit on Charlie Company last night.
他们发现地图
They found maps on them, man.
听说每个散兵坑都有地雷
Got a friend at Battalion, says they had every foxhole here fixed on.
知道我方的距离、林木线和地雷
Distances, tree lines, our claymores, everything.
情况不妙
This is bad, man.
- 我有不祥之兆 - 听说我们身在柬埔寨
- I got bad vibes here. - I also heard we're in Cambodia now.
柬埔寨？你在开玩笑
Cambodia? Man, you're kidding me.
你想见我？
You wanted to see me, sir?
拉姆治 伊利亚小组归你
Yeah, Ramucci. Looks like you got Elias' squad now.
小组？我不知道我的连叫小组
Squad? I didn't know we were still referring to this platoon as squads.
我要你去那两个坑
I want you to take those two holes, right there and there.
跟在上面的巴恩 和在下面的金联络
Tie it off with Barnes up here and King down there.
长官 对不起…
Begging your pardon, sir...
那两个坑距离太远 一个连队可以从中通过
...my two holes are so far apart, a regiment could run between them.
我只有五个军人活着
I have five live bodies left.
我不想听你的问题 新兵很快到
I don't want to hear your problems. You'll get new men any day.
你要和别人一样作战
Make do like everybody else.
- 我没有要求这个 - 我不想再听
- I didn't ask for this. - I don't want to hear it.
- 你不想再听？ - 对
- You don't want to hear it? - That's right.
因为老实说我毫不在乎
Because, to tell you the truth, I don't give a shit.
我不再在乎
I just don't give a flying fuck anymore.
我很高兴我不用和他们一起去
I'm glad I ain't going with them.
外面有一头饥饿的野兽
Somewhere out there is the beast and he hungry tonight.
真失败
What a fucking bummer.
只剩十天了 我仍要面对这一切
Ten days and a wake- up, and I'm still dealing with this shit.
你怎么了？
What's the matter with you?
你为什么不写信？
Why ain't you writing nobody?
你的父母呢？
What about your folks?
你向我提起的祖母怎样？
That grandma you told me about?
女朋友？
Girl?
你有父母吧？
You got parents, don't you?
一定有些亲密的人
There must be somebody.
没有
No, there's nobody.
你抽太多了
You been smoking too much of this shit.
你要控制一下 令人颓丧
Gotta control that. Bring a man down.
我记得你初来时什么都不懂
I remember when you first come out here to the bush, you's green as...
你可曾被无法 摆脱的错误缠绕着？
You ever get caught in a mistake you just can't get out of?
总有方法解决的
There's a way out of anything.
只要你振作精神
Just keep your pecker hard and your powder dry...
一定有方法的
...and the worm will turn.
你还有多少天？
How many days you short?
不只是我 而是整个事情
It's not just me. It's how the whole thing works.
像伊利亚般的人要牺牲
People like Elias get wasted.
巴恩那种人却能继续为所欲为
People like Barnes go on making up all the rules any way they want.
我们只能逆来顺受吗？
So, what do we do? Sit in the middle and suck on it.
我们不用理会那些事情
We just don't add up to dry shit.
谁说你需要的？ 你只需要活着离开这里
Whoever said we did? All you got to do is make it out of here...
然后每天快乐地生活
...and it's all gravy. Every day, the rest of your life. Gravy.
你是理想主义者
Oh, shit. Superlifer.
收拾你的行装 你的命令刚下达
Collect up your shit. Your orders just come through.
不要骗我
Man, don't fuck with me.
你要邀请信吗？
Oh, what do you need, a written invitation?
天啊! 他们做错事
Cocksucker! Oh, wow! The lifers done made a mistake!
他们竟然饶我一命
They cut me some slack!
你有十分钟时间赶去搭直升机
You got 10 minutes to make the last fucking chopper out of here.
因为如果你不上机…
Because if you're not on it...
我便会去
...I'm gonna be.
泰勒 法兰西准备好了
Taylor, Francis is coming up.
太好了 金 我为你感到高兴 回家吧!
That's great, King, I'm happy for you. Take it on home for me.
你有我的地址 你知道怎么联络我
You got my address. You know where to reach me anytime.
我要走了 我不想错过直升机
I gotta di di, Don't want to miss that chopper.
- 你没事吧？ - 我没事
- You okay? - Yeah, I'm okay.
记住放松点
Remember, take it easy.
不要想太多 别做傻瓜
Don't think too much. Don't you be no fool.
记住这里没有人是懦夫
Remember, ain't no such thing as a coward out here.
我的朋友
My man.
我送你出去
I'll walk you out, man.
金 保重
Take it easy, King.
- 我会的 - 再见
- I'll take it any way I can get it. - I hear you. Later.
很痛 中士 不要碰它
I'm pretty fucked up, sarge. Don't touch it!
我一定要上直升机
I gotta get on the chopper, man.
- 有什么问题？ - 他说不能走路
- So, what's the problem? - Says he can't walk.
可恶
Shit.
马丁…
Martin...
穿上靴子
...get your boots on.
下次给我见到你喷防蚊水…
And the next time I catch you spraying skeeter repellent on your feet...
我会送你上军事法庭
...I'll court- martial your nigger ass.
送我去吧
Then court- martial me, motherfucker!
逮捕我啊! 送我去坐牢吧
Bust my ass! Send me to fucking Long Binh!
下手吧
Do your fucking worst!
你们白人欺负我
You white folks got your last klick out of Junior!
奥尼尔 把蜈蚣拿来
O'Neill, get me that centipede.
- 中士？ - 是
- Sarge? - Yeah.
我找到那毛茸茸、红黑色的虫
That long, hairy, red and black bastard I found in the ammo crate.
我会把它放进他的伤口
I'm gonna put it in this boy's crotch.
我记得了
I remember now.
等一下
Hold up, man!
等一下好吗？
You just hold up and wait, okay?
我会走路了
Fuck it, I'll walk! I'll fucking walk!
我要和他同一个坑？
Fucking pussy! Sarge, I gotta have him in my hole?
对
Yeah.
我可以和你谈谈吗？
Bob, I'd like to speak to you a minute.
我不能再忍受了
I can't take it no more.
什么事？
Yeah, what is it?
我有伊利亚的假期 有三天
Bob, I got Elias' R and R. It's coming up in three days.
我想回去夏威夷见柏丝
I was thinking about going to Hawaii and see Patsy.
我从没向你要求过任何事
I never asked you for a thing over here.
坦白说…
Well, to be honest with you...
我想和金一起坐直升机回去 你觉得呢？
...I was hoping you'd put me on a chopper with King. What do you say?
我不能让你那样做
I can't do that for you.
你知道这里很需要人手
You know we need every swinging dick in the field.
你可以跟我说 我只是请三天假
You can talk to me, for chrissake! I'm just asking for three days.
我告诉你不可以
I am talking to you, Red. And I'm telling you no.
回到散兵坑
Get back in your foxhole.
我有不祥之兆 知道吗？
Bob, I've got a bad feeling on this one, all right?
我今次有不祥之兆
I mean I've got a bad feeling.
我觉得我不能活着离开这里
I don't think I'm gonna make it out of here.
你明白吗？
You understand what I'm saying?
每个人都会死的
Everybody gotta die sometime, Red.
可恶
Oh, shit!
混蛋们 再见
Goodbye, motherfuckers!
埋伏在哪里？
Where's that fucking ambush?
他们不会等 他们现在就来了
They ain't even waiting till later. It's fucking coming now, man.
现在就来了
Right fucking now.
乔利亚 我们所做的一切
You know, Junior? Some of the things we done, man...
我不觉得我们在做错事
...I don't feel like we done something wrong.
但有时…
But sometimes, man...
我有不祥的感觉
...I get this bad feeling.
我坦然对随军牧师说我喜欢这里
I told the padre the truth. I like it here.
你可以为所欲为 没有人理会你
You get to do what you want, nobody fucks with you.
你只用担心死亡
The only worry you got is dying.
反正死的时候你不会知道
And if that happens, you won't know about it...
那么担心什么？
...so, what the fuck, man?
我要和你同一个坑？
Shit. I got to be in this hole with you, man?
我早知道我不应该来
I just know I shouldn't have come.
不用担心 你和爱迪墨菲在一起
Don't you worry, Junior. You're hanging with Audie Murphy here.
B3、B6 给我座标… 完毕
Bravo 3, Bravo 6. Send me a grid, send me a grid. Over.
我不能 我们被困住了 他们在树丛里
I Can't, sir, We're pinned down, They're in the trees,
好 3A 冷静下来 我会立即派人去轰炸
Okay, 3 Alpha, now calm down, son. I'll get you a fire mission ASAP.
- 先会发放烟雾 - 中尉和电讯兵已经死了
- Smoke will be first. - Lieutenant and radioman are dead,
我找不到地图
I Can't find the map,
他们分布在四周 好几百个 我听到他们说越南话
They're all around us, Hundreds of them, I Can hear them talking gook,
3A 看着烟雾 告诉我要转向哪里
3 Alpha, spot that smoke and tell me where to shift.
冷静下来 撑着点 我们会救你
Just calm down. Hang in there. We'll get you out.
哪里被袭？完毕
Where did the rounds hit? Over.
3A6 你可以调整开火位置吗？完毕
3 Alpha 6, how about those rounds? Can you adjust fire? Over.
3A6 如果你不能说话 按键两次 完毕
3 Alpha 6, if you can't talk, just key your handset twice. Over.
糟了
Shit.
罗德里的坑被击中
Trip flare, Rodriguez's hole.
火箭榴弹
RPG.
- 泰勒、法兰西 - 这里
- Taylor. Francis. - Over here, man!
发生什么事？罗德里的坑被炸
What's going on? Rodriguez's hole just got nailed.
来了 附近布满越南兵
Here it is. We got gooks in the fucking perimeter.
完了…
Shit. That's it!
他们打败了A连
They got through Alpha Company. Anything that don't identify itself...
向任何不明物体开枪
...fucking blow it away.
妈的 空军正在赶来 他们会拼命投弹的
Fuck. Air strikes coming in. They'll be laying snake and nape.
不要离开散兵坑
Don't get out of your fucking holes. Stay right here.
糟了
Fuck.
他们在侦察我们
They're probing us.
他们不惜一切地攻入
They'll go up and down, trying to get through.
留在这里 冷静点 我很快回来
All right, stay here. Stay cool. I'll be right back.
F队 回音 威士忌 完毕
Foxtrot, Foxtrot, ECho, Whiskey, Over,
是谁？
Who is it?
不要开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
是埋伏 这边
It's the ambush. Over here, man, hurry!
- 糟了 - 水
- Shit. - Water!
他们到处都是 正走向这里
They're all over the place! Hundreds of them! Moving this way.
他们击溃我们 我们没有还击机会
They wiped us out! We didn't have a chance.
- 总部在哪里？ - 后面
- Where's the CP? - Back there.
快离开 他们不会停止的
Get out of here! They're on my ass! They ain't stopping for shit!
泰勒 我们走吧
Hey, Taylor, let's di di,
你走
You go.
那边
There.
停火…
No, hold it. Hold it.
快离开
Out of the hole! Fast!
快立刻出壕沟 他们想炸掉兵坑
Get out of the foxhole! They're gonna blow it!
走吧…
Let's go! Let's go!
快点走 快! 他们要炸掉…
Fuck's sake. Move your fucking ass! They're gonna blow...
很可怕
Fuck me.
等一下
Wait!
混蛋 死吧
Die, you motherfuckers!
很漂亮
It's fucking beautiful!
你在做什么？你去哪里？
What are you doing? Where are you going?
来吧
Come on, motherfuckers!
你们能做得更好
You can do better than that!
他们不断进攻
They just keep coming, man! Fuck this shit.
回来 你这个懦夫
Get back here, you gutless shit!
给我B连
Get me Bravo ASAP.
C连报告三个坑失守 需要增援
Charlie Company reports hand- to- hand, three holes are down. They need help.
立即派A连的两个小组前去 快!
Okay, get two squads from Alpha down there right away. Go, go!
空袭在哪里？
Where's that goddamn air strike?
你们去哪里？
Hey, you two! Where the fuck are you going?
联络不到任何人吗？
Can't you get anybody?
不行 联络不到巴恩他们
Negative contact. Can't raise Barnes, 2 Bravo, 2 Charlie, nothing!
- 给我联络总部 - 总部
- Get me 6! - Bravo 6!
- 柏加被击中 - 拉他进来
- Parker's hit! - Get him in!
他们正在攻入
They're coming through our line!
- 巴恩在哪里？ - 他死了 他们全都死了
- Where's Barnes?! - He's dead! They're all dead!
六队 中尉
Six, L.T.!
中尉 我们被袭击 我们会撤退
Captain, we've been overrun. We're pulling back. Over.
妈的! 撤退到哪里？ 到处都是他们
Goddamn it! Where will you pull back to? They're all over the perimeter!
你听着 你们要坚守作战
Now you be advised! You will hold in place and you will fight!
中尉 即是指你 六队通话完毕
That means you, lieutenant. Bravo 6 out.
这里被袭
We got zips in the wire down here.
收到 B6 但我们不能再接近了
Roger that, Bravo 6, Can't run it any Closer,
我们准备投弹 我们燃料充足
We're paCking snake and nape but we're bingo on fuel,
这是我的决定 投下所有炸弹
For the record, it's my call! Dump all you've got on my pos.
我再说一遍 投下所有炸弹
I say again, expend all remaining in my perimeter.
这是一场很棒的战争 B6通话完毕
It's a lovely fucking war. Bravo 6 out.
收到 这是你的决定
Roger your last, Bravo 6, We Copy it's your Call,
叫他们留守散兵坑 你们支持着
Get them in their holes, Hang tough, Bravo 6,
我们会从树顶投下炸弹
We are Coming CoCked for treetops,
巴恩
Barnes!
不要
No!
给我找军医
Get me a medic.
快去
Go on, boy!
下手吧
Do it.
小心 三点钟位置还有越兵活着
Look out, we got live gooks at 3:00.
快点
Come on, Elmo! Move your flea- bitten ass!
你没事吧？
You okay? You all right?
你能走动吗？
Can you walk?
这里需要军医
Hey, doc! We need a medic up here!
- 来吧 - 这里有伤兵
- Come on, Elmo. - Doc, we got wounded here!
战争一定是很激烈
That must have been some fucking fight.
只有你一个吗？
You alone here, man?
是
Yeah.
那些混球 他们留下我
Bunch of fucking faggots. They all left me.
122个受伤 仍在点算中
122 wounded and still counting.
估计有五百个伤者…
Estimate 500...
敌军22人阵亡 仍在点算中 完毕
...Victor Charlie K.l.A. 22 and still counting. Over.
泰勒 是你吗？
Taylor! That you?
法兰西
Hey, Francis.
- 你好吗？ - 我还好 你好吗？
- Hey, man, how you doing? - I'm okay. How you doing?
我很好
Fine, man. Just fine.
我们受过两次伤可以离开这里
Hey, dig it, we two- timers. We're gonna get out of here, boy.
在医院再见
I'm gonna see you in the hospital. We gonna get high, high. Yes, sir.
- 你好吗？ - 我没事
- How you doing? - I'm just fine, sir.
好 因为第二连由你指挥
Good, because you got 2nd Platoon.
是
Yes, sir.
- 准备好了吗？ - 好了
- Ready? - You bet.
现在回想一切…
I think now, looking back...
我们不是对抗敌人 而是自己
...we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves...
敌人就在我们心中
...and the enemy was in us,
战争对我来说现在已经完结
The war is over for me now...
但它永远会存留在我的心中
...but it will always be there the rest of my days,
伊利亚会和巴恩…
As I'm sure Elias will be...
为了像罗德所说的"灵魂的掌控"继续作战
...fighting with Barnes for, what Rhah Called, possession of my soul,
我有时会觉得…
There are times sinCe...
我是那两个父亲的儿子
...I have felt like the Child born of those two fathers,
但无论如何…
But be that as it may...
我们有责任重建社会…
...those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again,
教导别人我们认识的一切…
To teaCh to others what we know...
我们利用剩下的一生…
...and to try with what's left of our lives...
尝试找寻生命的意义
...to find a goodness and meaning to this life,
献给在越战牺牲的士兵